创世之初 冥冥之中
In the beginning, there was darkness...
随着轰的一声
and then, bang...
诞生了无限膨胀的
giving birth to an endless expanding existence...
时间 空间和物质
of time, space, and matter.
现在 所见超乎我们的想象
Now, see further than we've ever imagined...
超越了我们生存的限制
beyond the limits of our existence...
这个空间我们称之为"宇宙"
in a place we call "The Universe."
我们孤独吗?
Are we alone...
抑或宇宙的某处存在着另一颗类地行星呢?
or is there another Earth-Like planet somewhere in the universe?
我们一直对我们的下一代有一个奇妙的目标
We have a fantastic goal yet for the next generation...
那就是找到让我们缅怀老家的行星
which is to find planets that remind us of home.
我相信我们有望
I believe we're right on the brink...
利用科技的能力来回答这个问题
of having the technological capability to actually answer the question...
那是人类过去2000年以来一直在扪心自问的
that humanity has been asking itself for the last 2,000 years.
另一个地球可能就近在离我们最近的太阳系里
Another Earth could be as close as our nearest star system.
我们就站在能发现这些行星的门槛上了
We're right on the threshold...of being able to find these planets.
有可能是被怪异的太阳所扭曲的地球
There could be twisted Earths under bizarre suns.
我们能否发现那些地球
Can we find these other Earths as they float, hidden...
如果它们游荡 隐藏在宇宙数十亿颗恒星 数万亿颗行星中呢?
in the billions of stars and trillions of planets of the universe?
宇宙:另一个地球
宇宙间存在另一颗地球吗?
Is there another Earth in the universe?
这或许是最古老的想法之一
It's perhaps one of the oldest ideas...
自打人类能注视星空以来就耿耿于怀
since mankind was able to look up at the stars and wonder.
当年人们围坐在篝火旁
Back when people were sitting around their campfires...
仰望群星
and looking up at the stars...
把它们想象成篝火
and imagining them as other campfires...
其它种族围坐在旁边
with other tribes around them.
究竟什么是我们所指的另一个地球呢?
What exactly do we mean by another Earth?
它应该能维持类地生命
It should support Earth-Like life.
归结一下 生命需要三个最基本的东西才能生存
When you boil it down, life needs three very basic things to exist.
它需要某种液态介质来进行化学反应
It needs a liquid medium of some sort to do its chemical reactions in...
我们认为水是最合适的液态介质
and we think water is the most likely liquid medium.
它在宇宙间相当普遍
It's pretty prevalent in the universe.
我们还需要找到生命的基本组成部分
We also need to look for the basic building blocks of life...
可以帮助组成生命的分子
the molecules that can help to put life together...
你的DNA里的磷
the phosphorus in your DNA.
我们需要有能源
And we need to have an energy source.
结果就是类地行星上有水
It turns out that a terrestrial planet that has water on it...
几乎具备我们所需的所有这些东西
pretty much has all of those things we need.
并非所有能维持类地生命的行星
Not all planets capable of supporting Earth-Like life...
都必须是我们地球的拷贝不走样
would have to be carbon copies of our own Earth.
因此你可以将它看作是一系列不同类型的房子
So you can think of it like a series of different types of houses.
假如你来到一座城市 举个例子 会有豪宅
If you go into a city, for example, there will be grand mansions...
会有较小的 较适中的二居室小住宅
and there will be smaller, more modest little two-bedroom homes...
会有市民公寓以及摩天大楼
and there will be city studios and skyscrapers...
等等之类
and so on and so forth.
都住满了人
All of these house people.
所有这些都有助于安顿生命
All of these can help house life.
所以我们在琢磨
And so we think about that...
我们走进宇宙所看到的情形
when we go out into the universe looking.
我们将要看看各种不同种类的房子
We're going to be looking for houses of all different kinds...
敞开思绪 看看什么能维持生命
and keeping our minds open as to what could support life.
天文学家已经发现了300多颗日外行星
Astronomers have found over 300 exoplanets...
也就是 我们太阳系外的行星
that is, planets outside our solar system.
绝大多数是气体巨星
The vast majority are gas giants...
其发现要比我们地球这样的类地行星来得容易
which are easier to find than small terrestrial planets like our Earth.
为了打造分析那些类地行星的仪器
To build instruments to analyze those Earth-like planets...
我们必须提前预计到
we have to anticipate ahead of time...
类地行星大气层里有可能有何种化学物质
what the chemicals might be in that Earth-like atmosphere.
基于那个原因 我们需要理论 需要模型
For that reason, we need theory, we need models.
维多利亚.梅道斯埋头于行星建模的专研
Victoria Meadows is in the planet modeling business.
她领导的虚拟行星实验室
She heads up the Virtual Planet Laboratory...
坐落在西雅图的华盛顿大学
at Seattle's University of Washington.
其团队 分布在全国各地的机构里
The group, spread across institutions around the country...
构建着未探索宇宙间可能存在的世界
builds worlds that may exist in the yet unexplored universe.
虚拟行星实验室让我们去模拟
The Virtual Planetary Laboratory allows us to simulate...
太空中的行星的模样
what planets might look like from space...
其环境究竟是怎么回事
and what their environments might be like...
实际上是超前去探索
in advance of actually discovering these things...
宇宙间的这些东西
out there in the universe.
所以说 它让我们去探索行星可能的模样
So it allows us to explore what planets might be like.
在虚拟行星实验室里 构建奇幻世界
In the Virtual Planet Lab, fantastic worlds can be built...
如科幻小说家那样
like a science fiction novelist...
将超级计算机作为写作搭档
with a supercomputer as a writing partner.
我们可以拿上地球之类的东西
So we can take something that's like the Earth...
不过我们会取走太阳
but we rip away the Sun, and we replace it...
用不同大小和温度的恒星来取代它
with a star of different size and temperature.
所以我们在虚拟行星实验室里所做的
So what we've done with the Virtual Planetary Laboratory...
就是模拟开始就表现为地球类的行星
is modeled planets that started out as Earth-like...
将它们围绕着恒星 其温度
and put them around stars that were much hotter...
其紫外线的强度都要比我们的太阳来得厉害
with much stronger UV radiation, for example, than our own Sun.
这些模型可以产生千奇百怪的候补地球
The models can produce bizarre alternate Earths...
生长的植物有鲜红的
filled with plants that are bright red...
橙色的
orange...
甚至墨黑的
or even pitch-black.
光合作用可以相差很大
Photosynthesis can vary greatly...
随照射的阳光而定
depending on the light of the star that's shining on it.
环绕F型星的行星 举个例子
Planets around F stars, for example...
阳光蓝得厉害
where the light from the star is much bluer...
那里的植物倾向于吸收更多的蓝光
the plants there will tend to absorb more blue light.
所以那些植物极有可能
And so those plants could potentially...
更多地发射红光 橙光 黄光
be more likely to reflect red, orange, and yellow light...
因此就会呈现出红色 橙色 黄色
and so will appear red, orange, and yellow to us.
植物生长的行星所围绕的是颗较弱的恒星 其色彩的进化
Plants on a world around weaker stars could evolve their coloration...
将会利用它们得到的每一点能量
to use every bit of energy falling an them.
如果你来到比我们太阳温度低得多的恒星 M型星
lf you go down to much cooler stars than our Sun, to M stars...
围绕M型星的行星上的植物有可能 其实是黑色的
plants on planets around M stars might, in fact, be black...
因为它们想吸收尽可能多的阳光
'cause they want to absorb as much light as possible...
进行光合反应 补充能量
to do their photosynthesis and to feed.
还有水世界行星
And then there's the water-world planet...
一个理论上的地球围绕着不稳定的M型星
a theoretical Earth circling a volatile M-type star...
它致命的辐射爆发连续不断地攻击行星
that constantly hits the planet with outbursts of deadly radiation.
生命在行星的表面将如何去应付呢?
And how does life cope on the surface of that planet?
遇上熊熊燃烧的M型星 有无可能存在生命呢?
Is it possible to have life even when you have a flaring M star?
原来你可以生活在
It turns out that you can actually live...
环绕M型星的行星的水面9米之下
about nine meters under water on a planet around an M star...
还是能摆脱最厉害的耀斑
and still escape the worst of the flares...
同时还是能获得足够的能量
but still have enough light...
来进行光合作用 存活下去
to be able to do photosynthesis and to survive.
这里看出去一切良好
Everything looks good from here.
随着未来的探索任务的逐步拟定
And as future exploration missions are being drawn up...
许多科学家正聚焦于怎样才能
many scientists are focusing on what it would take...
检测到遥远星球上的生命的副产品
to detect the by-products of life on a distant planet.
生命产生的气体
Life produces gases.
生命的气息 你可以闻到的
Life stinks. You can smell it.
我们要搜寻那些气息
And we're going to look for those gases...
利用这些高分辨率光谱仪
with these high-resolution spectrometers.
因此我们实际需要做的
So what we really need to do...
就是获取其它类地行星发出的光
is take the light from another Earth-like planet...
进行分析
and analyze it to find out...
并找出其大气层里的化学成分
what the chemical composition of that atmosphere is.
找到行星的所在位置
Finding the locations of planets...
是加州大学伯克利分校的天文学家杰夫.马西的擅长
is something that UC Berkeley astronomer Geoff Marcy is very good at.
他和他的天文学同事 保罗.巴特勒
He and his astronomy colleague, Paul Butler...
被认为找到的日外行星比谁都多
are credited with finding more exoplanets than anyone else.
远离其主星的行星会非常寒冷
A planet that's farther from its host star will be very cool...
因此有一个区域 所处的地方
and so there's a domain in between...
我们有时称其为金发地带
that we sometimes call the Goldilocks zone...
也就是宜居地带 那里的温度恰到好处
or the habitable zone where the temperature is just right.
所谓的恰到好处 我的意思是 不冷也不热
And by just right, I mean, lukewarm...
所以那里的水是液态的
so that water would be in liquid form.
当然 液态水是生命的先决条件
And, of course, it's liquid water that's the prerequisite for life.
我们观察其他行星时
When we look at other planets...
会发问 其他行星上会有生命吗?
and we ask, "Could there be life on other planets?
我首先要问的是 那颗行星上能否维持液态水吗?
my first question is, "Could that planet support liquid water?"
能 我感兴趣
Yes? I'm interested.
否 我就不感兴趣
No? I'm not interested.
总而言之 让我看到水
It all comes down to, show me the water.
水是一种神奇的物质
Water is an amazing substance.
我们 坦率说 很幸运
We are, frankly, fortunate...
宇宙间存在着叫做水的东西
that the universe has something called water.
它是了不起的宇宙鸡尾酒混合器
It's the great cosmic cocktail mixer.
水是关键的物质 让化学反应得以发生
Water is the critical stuff that allows the chemical reactions to take place...
最终导致生命
that eventually lead to life.
不过这个液态水得以存在的特殊区域
But this special zone where liquid water can exist...
因地而异
varies from place to place.
如果恒星是高热的O型星
If a star is a hot O-type...
那么这个区域将会远离太阳
the zone will be farther out from a sun.
如果是颗低温的M型星 这个区域就比较靠近
If it's a cool M-type, the zone will be closer in.
它甚至还随着时间而改变
And it even changes with time.
恒星并非一成不变的
Stars are not stable.
即使我们自己地球这个舒适的宜居之地
Even our own comfy habitable zone here on Earth...
也会在几百万年里发生变化
will change in a few million years...
到时我们的太阳将会变老 更加炙热
when our Sun grows older and much hotter.
目前的技术尚不能拍摄到
Current technology doesn't exist...
遥远的日外行星的照片
to take pictures of distant exoplanets...
因此天文学家利用太阳系里的恒星
so astronomers use the solar system's star...
来作为行星的代理人
as a sort of proxy for a planet...
因为两者都形成于同样物质的行星盘
since both were formed from the same planetary disk of material.
我们是如何知道恒星的成分的呢?
How do we know what a star is made out of?
我们不会去那里获取样本
We don't go there and sample it.
你的实验将会被融化的
Your experiment would melt.
天文学家韦斯.特劳布主导的项目
Astronomer Wes Traub heads up the effort...
航天局的喷气推进实验室
by NASA's Jet Propulsion Laboratory...
提出用下一代的仪器
to come up with the next generation of instruments...
来观察我们太阳系以外的行星
that will look at planets outside our solar system.
我们所做的就是我们只是简单地观察它
What we do is we just simply look at it...
把光分成各种颜色
and we break the light up into different colors.
这是几百年前牛顿所做的事
This was done several hundred years ago by Newton.
他发现 如果你将一个棱镜放到阳光里
He discovered that if you put a prism in a ray of sunlight...
它会将光线分成蓝色 绿色 红色
it breaks it up into blue, green, red.
你观察这些不同的颜色
And you look at these different colors...
你会突然发现非常惊人的东西
and you discover something very startling all of a sudden.
有些部分的颜色缺失了
There are parts where colors are missing...
这些缺失的颜色
and these missing colors are a fingerprint...
就是你所观察的太阳成分的指纹
of the constituent of the sun that you're looking at.
利用当代技术
With current technology...
我们无法直接看到
we can't directly view a spectrum of a planet...
我们太阳系外行星的光谱
outside our solar system.
不过 最终 更加强大的仪器
But, eventually, more powerful instruments...
将会让我们利用同样的技术
will allow us to use the same technique...
去获取行星的指纹 以证明生命的存在
to fingerprint a planet for evidence of life.
如果我们能看到行星发出的光
If we look at that light from the planet...
用棱镜等之类的东西来分解
and break it up with a prism or something similar...
我们就可以知晓该行星的成分
we can tell what the planet is made out of...
这样我们就可以知道我们的行星是否有氧气
and that's how we know whether our planet has oxygen...
类似于我们的大气层
like our atmosphere...
大气层里是否有水蒸汽
whether it has water vapor in the atmosphere...
是否有臭氧 二氧化碳 一氧化二氮
whether it has ozone, carbon dioxide, and nitrous oxide.
不过宇宙中没有一成不变的东西的
But nothing in the universe stays the same over time.
我们地球在45亿年前形成时
When our Earth formed 4 1/2 billion years ago...
它的大气层与现在是大相径庭的
it had a very different atmosphere than it has now.
它挑战着梅多斯和她团队的预期
It's a challenge that Meadows and her team anticipate...
他们所构建的其他类地行星的模型
as they build their models of other Earth-like planets.
我们目光短浅
We would be very shortsighted...
光寻找处于同一发展阶段的富氧行星
to look just for an oxygen-rich planet...at the same stage of development.
所以问题是 一旦我们出去寻找宜居世界时
So the thing is, when we go out to look for habitable worlds...
它们就会千差万别了
they could all be extremely different.
它们会是形形色色的
They could be very diverse.
要是我们找到了另一个地球
And if we find another Earth...
有机会发现文明
what are the chances we'll find a civilization on it...
并与之联系吗?
that we can communicate with?
会有一定数量的智能文明
What's the number of intelligent civilizations...
存在于宇宙的其它地球上吗?
that might exist on other Earths in the universe?
要不要必须进行这样的计算呢?
What would have to go into such a calculation?
有多少恒星存在?
How many stars are there?
有多少恒星带有行星?
How many of those stars have planets?
有多少行星足以拥有水呢?
How many of those planets are close enough to have water...
等等等等
and on and on.
那是天文学家卡尔.萨根和弗兰克.德雷克
That's a problem that astronomers Carl Sagan...
几十年前所提出的问题
and Frank Drake took on decades ago.
德雷克提出一个问题
Drake came up with an equation...
估计光我们银河系一个
that estimated that up to a million civilizations may exist...
就有多达百万个文明可能存在
in just our Milky Way alone.
德雷克方程就是这一系列的数字
The Drake Equation is this series of numbers...
试图以这样的方式组合在一起
that are trying to be put together in such a way...
给我们一种方法 来更加严谨地估算
to give us a kind of way of even closely estimating...
会有多少其它智能文明的存在
how many other intelligent civilizations are out there.
彼得.沃德 生物学和地质学教授
Peter Ward, a professor of biology and geology...
供职于西雅图的华盛顿大学
at Seattle's University of Washington...
认为德雷克方程大大地高估了
thinks the Drake Equation greatly overestimates...
可能存在于宇宙其它地球上的
the number of advanced civilizations...
发达文明的数量
that could exist on other Earths in the universe.
沃德和天文学教授唐.布朗利的著作《珍稀地球》
Ward and astronomy professor Don Brownlee's book "Rare Earth"...
阐述了为何他们认为复杂生命 动物 比如人类
explains why they think complex life, animal life, like humans...
在宇宙间十分稀有
may be rare in the universe.
我们一开始就认为它将涉及的
We began to think that it was just too simplistic...
其他因素过于简单化了
that there's other stuff involved.
沃德枚举了一些要素
Ward cites a number of factors...
他认为那会降低原先德雷克所估计的
that he thinks would lower the original Drake estimates...
有多少复杂生命存在于银河系里
of how much complex life could exist in the Milky Way...
乃至宇宙间
and, by extension, the universe.
首先 板块构造
First of all, plate tectonics.
板块构造就是大陆漂移
Plate tectonics is continental drift...
人们不禁要问
and one wonders why would that have anything to do...
这与行星上出现生命的频率有什么关系
with the frequency of life on the planet.
板块构造也会产生元素的循环
Plate tectonics also produces a recycling of elements...
那种循环会产生某些最基本的东西
and that recycling does some very fundamental things.
它所产生的最基本的东西 就是温度范围
The most fundamental thing it does, it produces a temperature gauge.
就像是行星上的温控器
It's like a thermostat on the planet.
要是我们感觉太热 板块构造过程就会帮助我们冷却
lf we get too warm, plate tectonic processes help us cool off.
另外行星上要存在有金属
Then there's the presence of metal on the planet.
其次 如果你想成为一个智能文明
Secondly, if you want to be an intelligent civilization...
你最好要有金属
you better have metal.
金属很难在火星或金星这样的行星上找到
Metal is hard to find on a planet like Mars or Venus.
板块构造把一切都循环起来 产生裂缝
Plate tectonics rotates everything, causes cracks.
把重金属搬送上来
Up come the heavy metals.
此外我们还需要什么?
What else do we need?
我们需要有好木星
We need a good Jupiter.
有一颗木星之类的气体巨星 以其强大的引力
Having a gas giant like Jupiter, with its strong gravitational pull...
处在太阳系的外围
in the outer reaches of a solar system...
护卫着内部的行星 那些潜在的地球
protects the inner planets, those potential Earths...
免遭频繁的惨烈撞击
from frequent catastrophic impacts.
原来这些木星的引力扫除小行星和彗星
And the reason is those Jupiters sweep up gravitationally...
将它们抛出去
the asteroids and the comets, flinging them away...
使得地球幸免于
allowing the Earth to survive...
那些碎片的许多撞击
without so many impacts by that debris.
因而就是那些保护星让生命得以延续
And so it's those protective Jupiters that allow life to proceed...
免遭这些会造成大规模灭绝的小行星
without impacts by these asteroids and comets...
与彗星的撞击
that would cause mass extinctions...
那实际上曾发生在了恐龙身上
as indeed happened to the dinosaurs.
6500万年前 一颗小行星撞击地球
Sixty-five million years ago, an asteroid hit Earth...
抹去了地球上几乎所有的恐龙
and wiped out most of the dinosaurs on the planet.
那些恐龙的灭绝是因为木星的工作懈怠
Those dinosaurs went out because Jupiter failed on the job...
应该被炒鱿鱼
and should have been fired.
那天它是坏木星
Bad Jupiter that day.
它让其中一颗小行星闯入
It let one of these asteroids sweep by...
然而我们看到了它惯常的做法
but we've seen what it usually does.
彗星苏梅克列维一头撞进木星
Comet Shoemaker-Levy that smashed into Jupiter...
在上世纪末
at the last part of the last century.
那就是木星通常所为
That's what Jupiter generally does.
因此好木星是好东西
So good Jupiters are good things to have...
可以用来保持平衡
and you can make equations for this.
在考虑可居住的行星时
When considering the habitability of planets...
大多数天文学家都突出强调将要寻找的行星
most astronomers place great emphasis on finding worlds...
放在恒星周围的宜居区域里
in the habitable zone around a star.
但是沃德和他的合作者认为
But Ward and his co-author believe...
行星在更大的星系里的位置也十分关键
that a planet's position within the larger galaxy is also critical.
那就是为什么我们定义或界定了
So that's why we have defined, or did define...
我们称之为星系的宜居区域的东西:
something we call the galactic habitable zone:
那个区域在一个星系里 既不能太近 也不能太远
that area within a galaxy, not too close, not too far.
我们星系里的金发区域恰到好处
It's a Goldilocks area within our galaxy that's just right.
他们提出了九大要素
They came up with nine factors...
来构成所谓的星系宜居区域
that make up a so-called galactic habitable zone.
首先要关注在星系里的位置
First, position in the galaxy was considered.
远离杀手中子星
Away from killer neutron stars...
黑洞
black holes...
以及致命的伽马射线暴
and deadly gamma-ray bursts.
他们计入了恒星带有行星的百分比
They included the percentage of stars that have planets...
以及具有微生物生命的百分比
and the percentage that have microbial life.
他们甚至还估算了行星要多久
They even estimated how often planets...
才有可能将其所有的生命通通灭绝
might have all their life extinguished.
地球本身在1998年就可能勉强躲过了这样一劫
Earth itself may have narrowly missed such an event in 1998.
当时一颗致密的恒星叫做磁星
Then a high density star called a magnetar...
爆发出致命的伽马射线
burped out a flare of deadly gamma rays...
在十分之二秒里所释放的能量
unleashing as much energy in two-tenths of a second...
相当于太阳未来10万年里所产生的能量
as the Sun will put out in the next 100,000 years.
幸运的是 该磁星距离地球有2万光年之远
Luckily, the magnetar was located 20,000 light-years away from Earth.
有一个非常好的问题会提出
A really good question would be to ask...
要是那颗磁星的爆发不是在2万光年远
what would have happened had that magnetar that burped...
而是在1万光年远 会有什么结果呢?
not been 20,000 light-years away, but 10,000 light-years away?
会不会有这样的情景
Could there be a case where we have something...
我们遇上就几百光年里的东西?
within a few hundred light-years?
如果是那个情景 新的计算表明
If that were the case, new calculations suggest...
它会在一次爆发中扑的一下吹走我们的大气层
it could punch our atmosphere off-- whoof--in one burst...
你会说 我不能呼吸了
and you go, "l can't breathe."
那可是悲惨的 是完全有可能的
Now, that's catastrophic, and that is totally possible.
人类可能只是宇宙中的侥幸
Humans may be just a cosmic fluke in the universe.
德雷克方程的乐观假设
The optimistic assumptions of the Drake Equation...
恐怕得不到天文学家
may just not hold up with what astronomers have learned...
过去几十年认识的支持
in the past decades.
德雷克方程是个不切实际的构想
The Drake Equation was a fantastic construct...
不过它形成于1960年代
but it was done in the 1960s.
我们现在认识得更多了
We know so much more now.
因此我们所添加的东西是当时所不知道的
So we've added in stuff that wasn't known then.
我认为这使得它更加准确了
And I think it makes it more accurate.
但是 最终 它也将数字给降了下来
But, ultimately, it also brings down the numbers.
百万个文明
And the million civilizations...
我不认为可以得到当前的认识的支持
I do not think can be supported by current understanding.
那么究竟有多少其它地球 支持着先进的文明
So how many other Earths, supporting advanced civilizations...
是他所认为有可能存在于我们的银河系里的呢?
does he think may exist in our Milky Way?
我一再被要求做出一个预言
I've been asked over and over to make a prediction...
我会说 啊 我们知道至少是一个
and I'd say, "Well, we know it's at least one."
是一个以上 我认为
It's more than one, l think.
不过我认为是超过一个 但大大少于百万个
But I think it's more than one, but way less than a million.
寻找到其它文明是有可能的
Locating another civilization may happen...
因为天文学家正全力以赴寻找其它类地行星
as astronomers concentrate on looking for other Earth-like planets.
不过发现那些地球从一开始
But finding those Earths in the first place...
对科学家来说 就是一个巨大的技术挑战
is a huge technical challenge for scientists.
不同于已分类登记的恒星
Unlike the stars that have been catalogued...
行星利用现代技术尚无法看到
planets can't be seen using current technology.
行星 从数光年远去审视
A planet, when examined from light-years away...
几乎就紧挨着它的太阳
is almost on top of its sun...
从我们太阳系外来看的话
as viewed from outside our solar system.
更糟的是 类地行星
And to make matters worse, an Earth-like planet...
即使是比我们地球大几倍
even one many times larger than our Earth...
相对其母星 也只发出微乎其微的光线
reflects only an infinitesimal amount of light compared to its star.
这里我们有一颗明亮的恒星
So here we have a bright star...
一颗昏暗100亿倍的行星
and a planet which is 10 billion times fainter.
很难想象100亿倍是什么概念
It's hard to imagine what 10 billion times really is.
不过我们考虑这个概念有好多方法
But the way many of us think of this is...
假设你有一只萤火虫 很小的萤火虫
suppose you have a firefly, a very small firefly...
发出微弱的光
a very weak light.
假设萤火虫
And suppose that firefly is orbiting around...
围绕着灯塔转
or flying around a lighthouse.
假设你试图从3000英里外
And suppose you're trying to look at this firefly...
观察萤火虫围绕着这灯塔转
flying around this lighthouse from 3,000 miles away.
情况就是这样
That's something what it's like.
假设你可以发现萤火虫的光斑
Let's assume you could find that speck of a firefly...
从国家的另一头看
from across the country...
那么你就必须找到萤火虫的呼吸
and then you had to figure out what that firefly is breathing...
通过分析它吐出的气体
by analyzing the gas it's exhaling.
那就是天文学家所面临的挑战
That's the challenge that faces an astronomer...
他首先要发现行星
who first has to find a planet...
然后看看其大气层是否如地球一般
then figure out how Earth-like its atmosphere is.
不过天文学家已经找到了间接的方法
But astronomers have figured out indirect ways...
来寻找日外行星
to find extrasolar planets.
假如这是颗恒星 非常明亮 这是颗行星
If that were the star and very bright, and this were the planet...
当它走到恒星的前面时 恒星就会变暗
and it moved in front of that star, the star would get dimmer...
你就会注意到它的
and you would notice that.
这就是所谓的搜寻行星的凌日方法
It's called the transit method of discovering a planet...
因为它依靠观察行星穿越
since it depends on seeing the travel or transit...
或经过遥远的恒星
of a planet across a distant star.
它在前面时阻挡了一定量的光
The amount of light it blocks when it's in front...
就会告诉我们该行星会有多大
tells us how big the planet is.
因此我们就用它来了解 它是水星一般的小行星
So we use that to understand if it's a small planet like Mercury...
还是地球般的行星
a planet like the Earth...
或者是木星那样的巨星
or a huge giant like that of Jupiter.
我们利用其轨道周期和恒星的温度
And we use the orbital period and the temperature of the star...
来了解它是否处在宜居区域里
to tell us if it's in the habitable zone.
轨道周期就是行星围绕其母星所化的时间
The orbital period is how long a planet takes to go around its star.
它会一直运转
It would go on its way...
一年后又回来 周而复始
and come back again a year later and do it over again.
那个周期与恒星的类型和大小结合在一起
When that period is combined with the type and size of the star...
该信息就会告诉科学家 如果有行星发现
the information will tell scientists if the planets that are found...
那就有可能是在宜居区域里的
are potentially in a habitable zone.
凌日方法是有效的 只要观察者或望远镜
The transit method works if the observer or the telescope...
和恒星及其行星处在同一个平面上
is in the same plane as the star and its planets.
但是如果你高于或低于该星系
But if you're above or below the system...
则另一项技术 即所谓的无线电速度法
another technique, called the radio velocity method...
可能会派上用场
might be used.
该方法依靠对遥远恒星的仔细观察
That method depends on careful observations of a distant star...
观察它是否被看不见的日外行星的引力
to watch if it's being gravitationally tugged...
来回拽拉
back and forth by an unseen exoplanet.
天文学家可以使用该信息
Astronomers can use that information...
计算出影响该恒星的
to figure out details about the exoplanet...
日外行星的细节
that's influencing the star.
配备了这些手段
Equipped with these tools...
天文学家发现了数以百计的行星
astronomers are finding hundreds of planets...
有些是天文学教科书上从未想到过的:
some never dreamed of in astronomy textbooks:
超级地球
Super Earths...
热木星
hot Jupiters...
甚至还有一些我们地球的近亲
and even some close cousins to our own Earth.
在宇宙间数十亿颗恒星中
In the search for other Earths...
搜索其他地球的过程中
in the billion of stars in the universe...
天文学家发现了恒星成分
astronomers have found a relationship between the composition of a star...
与其潜在的行星
and the probability that it may have planets...
以及类地与其它行星之间的关系
both Earth-like and otherwise.
具有重元素的恒星
The stars that have heavier elements in them...
铁 镍 硅
the iron and the nickel and the silicon...
拥有重元素是有充分理由的
have heavier elements for a good reason.
那些恒星形成于
Those stars formed out of molecular clouds...
银河系里的分子云
in the Milky Way galaxy...
塌落形成了恒星
that collapsed down to form the star.
在那个过程中 其周围留下了一些胎盘物质
And in so doing left some placental material around them...
最终凝结成了行星
that eventually coagulated into the planets.
理所当然
So it makes sense that stars that formed...
由大量重元素形成的恒星
with lots of heavy elements...
所形成的行星也具有大量的重元素
will form planets that also have lots of heavier elements.
天文学家将恒星中的重元素比例称为
Astronomers call the proportion of heavy elements in a star...
它的金属度
its metallicity.
但是 那并不一定意味着
But that doesn't necessarily mean...
它具有大量的传统意义上的金属
it has a lot of metal in the conventional sense.
金属 对天文学家来说
Metal, for an astronomer...
是所有比氢或氦重的元素
is any element that's heavier than hydrogen or helium.
因此 在天文学家看来 锂是金属
So, in astronomer-speak lithium is a metal...
硫是金属 氯是金属
sulfur is a metal, chlorine is a metal...
而不只是铁 金 银之类的元素
and not just elements like iron, gold, and silver.
类地日外行星
An Earth-like exoplanet...
不仅需要其成分中有重元素
not only needs heavy elements in its composition...
以及处在恒星的宜居区域里
and to be in a star's habitable zone...
同时还需要有合适的大小来维持生命
it also needs to be the right size to sustain life.
合适的大小意味着它可以保有其大气层
Right size means it can hold onto its atmosphere...
具有板块构造和火山
and have plate tectonics and volcanoes...
这两者被认为是调节行星温度的关键
both considered critical to regulating a planet's temperature.
要做到这一切 天文学家估计
To do all this, astronomers estimate...
最小的行星可能是地球质量的三分之一
that the smallest a planet can be is one-third of Earth's mass.
最高 宜居行星
On the high side, a habitable planet...
是不可能超过地球质量的10倍的
cannot be greater than 10 times our Earth's mass.
日外行星的存在
The very existence of exoplanets...
从理论成为现实只是过去10年里的事情
as gone from theory to reality only in the last decade.
10年前
A little over 10 years ago...
我们还根本不知道有日外行星
we had no known extrasolar planets at all.
我们唯一所了解的行星 就是那些围绕着我们太阳的
The only planets we knew of were those orbiting our Sun...
现在我们知道了有行星围绕着其它恒星
and now we know of planets orbiting other stars.
当然 对这些行星真正让人兴奋的
And, of course, what's really exciting about these planets...
就是其中有些有可能是可居住的
is that some of them may be habitable...
因此说不定其中有些会存在生命
and so there's a chance that there's life on some of them.
在数百个日外行星中
Of the hundreds of exoplanets found...
有些有可能并不遵循类似于
some may not follow the familiar blueprint of planets...
我们太阳系行星的蓝图
in our solar system.
我们发现这些怪异的木星 其轨道非常靠近其母星
We found these bizarre Jupiters that orbit very close to their star.
它们被烤得滚烫
They're blow-torched hot...
这些木星无疑太靠近其母星了
and these Jupiters undoubtedly got close to their star...
不断往里靠近
by migrating inward.
有时 木星般大小的行星的形成
Sometimes, the formation of a Jupiter-mass planet...
会是星系中类地行星的丧钟
can be kind of a death knell for terrestrial planets in the system.
要是我们倒霉透顶
And what if we had been unlucky enough...
在我们太阳系里也有这样一颗木星会怎么样呢?
to have such a Jupiter in our solar system?
它就会将地球弹出轨道
It would have slingshot the Earth right out of its orbit...
到广袤 阴冷的外太空去
into the vast, cold darkness of outer space...
地球最终会毫无生机 变成阴冷的石头
and the Earth would eventually die off as a cold, dark hulk.
有300多颗日外行星被发现了
Over 300 exoplanets have been discovered...
更多的还在发现中
and more are being found all the time.
不过大多数是庞大的气体巨星
But the majority are monstrously huge gas giants...
成为类地行星的希望不大
that hold little promise of being truly Earth-like.
在飞马星座里 距离地球约50光年
In the Pegasus constellation, some 50 light-years from Earth...
可以看到行星51飞马座b
the planet 51 Pegasi b can be found.
它是我们太阳系外发现的第一颗行星
It was the first planet discovered outside our solar system...
大如木星的气体巨星
a gas giant as big as Jupiter...
但是其轨道非常靠近母星
but orbiting much closer to its star.
它围绕其太阳一圈只有4天
It races around its sun in just four days.
行星70室女座b比飞马座更远
The planet 70 Virginis b is even farther away than Pegasi...
有60光年
at 60 light-years.
其质量是我们木星的7.5倍
It's 7 1/2 times as massive as our Jupiter.
起初 它被认为是在恒星的宜居区域里
At first, it was believed to be in the habitable zone of the star...
所以它被昵称为金发姑娘
so it was nicknamed Goldilocks.
后来计算表明 它有一个偏心轨道
Later calculations showed that it had an eccentric orbit...
将其带到距离其太阳的2700万英里内
that brought it to within 27 million miles of its sun...
那里热不可耐
which is roasting hot.
因此它就不再被认为是处在宜居范围内了
So it's no longer considered to be in a habitable range.
这颗巨大的气体巨星 特雷斯4
The massive gas giant, Trace 4...
其直径超过了我们木星的1.5倍
is over 1 1/2 times the diameter of our Jupiter...
让它成为了迄今为止所发现的最大的行星
making it the largest planet found so far.
它距离地球1400光年
It's 1,400 light-years from Earth.
这颗气体巨星 尽管它比木星大多了
This gas giant, even though it's much larger than Jupiter...
但是其质量却是有木星的四分之三多一点
only has a little over 3/4 of its mass.
它是一颗热木星 围绕其太阳一圈只要3.5天
It's a hot Jupiter, zooming around its sun in only 3 1/2 days.
天文学家一直没能发现
Astronomers haven't been able to find...
我们太阳系外真正的类地行星
true Earth-like planets outside our solar system...
因为他们尚未能够发现
because they've not yet been able to detect...
这种相对较小的类似我们地球的岩质行星
such relatively small rocky planets as our Earth.
该技术只是尚未出现
The technology is just not there yet.
不过天文学家非常有幸
But astronomers are having more luck...
发现了所谓的超级地球
finding what are termed Super Earths.
人们实际上能够发现
People are actually being able to discover planets...
有可能处在其它恒星周围的宜居区域里的行星
that could potentially be in a habitable zone around other stars.
这里的一个典型的例子就是叫做格雷斯581c的行星
And one classic example of this is a planet called Gliese 581c.
格雷斯581星系
The Gliese 581 system...
距离地球约20.5光年
is located about 20 1/2 light-years from Earth...
在天秤座里
in the Libra constellation.
格雷斯581c的质量是地球的5倍
Gliese 581c has five times the mass of our Earth.
曾指望581c会成为首个类地行星
There were hopes that 581 c would be the first Earth-like planet...
在某个恒星的宜居区域里发现
found in the habitable zone of a star...
但证明错了
but that turned out to be wrong.
或许它站错了队
Probably it's a little bit on the wrong side of the fence...
结果它没成为超级地球
so that one, instead of being a Super Earth...
也许成了超级金星
is probably a Super Venus.
它类似我们的金星 站在了高热的一边
It's like our own Venus, way on the hot side...
可能有600度的温度
with possible 600-degree temperatures...
但是个头比金星大多了
but also more massive than Venus.
但是格雷斯581c有一个稍远稍冷一点的亲戚
But Gliese 581 c has a relative a little farther out and cooler.
它叫格雷斯581 d
It's named Gliese 581 d.
这颗星处在宜居区的远端
And this one is at the far back end...
那里相当寒冷
of the habitable zone where it's quite cold.
你最初看到它时
When you initially look at it...
你会想 哇 也许那里太冷了一点吧
you think, "Well, maybe that's a bit too cold."
不过现在看来
But it turns out that if the planet...
如果行星假定有充分的温室气体
potentially has enough greenhouse gases...
就有可能让该行星保持温暖
it might be possible to make that planet warm.
另一个有希望的类地行星可能是HD 69830 d
Another promising Earth-like planet may be HD 69830 d.
这是颗大行星 是我们地球大小的17倍
This is a big planet, 17 times the size of our Earth.
它距离我们太阳系约42光年
It's about 42 light-years away from our solar system...
在船尾座里
in the constellation Puppis.
HD 69830 d 是可能会形成生命的潜在行星
HD 69830 d is a potential planet where life could form...
因为它具有近乎合适的温度
because it has approximately the right temperature.
该行星的温度
The planet could have a temperature...
介于金星与地球之间
between that of Venus and Earth...
它有接近圆形的轨道 意味着它不会受到
and it has a close-to-circular orbit, meaning it won't get toasted...
其所围绕的恒星的煎熬
by close encounters with the star it's orbiting.
因此你可以看到有水
So you can have liquid water.
该行星的质量或许并不很理想
The mass of the planet is maybe not so good.
其质量是地球的17倍
It's about 17 times the mass of the Earth...
有可能是岩质实心球
which could be a solid ball of rock...
或也可能是个气体球 类似于我们太阳系里的海王星
or it could also be a gas ball like Neptune in our solar system.
在航天局未来的行星发现之旅中
When NASA's able to fly future planet-finding missions...
预计天文学家能够获得其光谱
it's expected that astronomers will be able to get a spectrum...
给我们带来有关该行星
that will give us much more information...
成分的很多信息
about the composition of the planet.
他们能够弄清楚该行星是否有固体的地表
They may be able to figure out if the planet has a solid surface...
还是它就是一个水世界
or that it's a water world...
或者完全别样的东西
or perhaps something else entirely.
搜索其它地球已经把天文学家带到了
The search for other Earths has taken astronomers...
数光年外的我们的太空邻居那里
light-years from our neighborhood in space.
但是我们自己的太阳系里 会不会有另一个地球存在呢?
But could another Earth exist in our own solar system?
虽然天文学家观察星系
While astronomers look at star systems...
有N多光年远
many light-years away...
寄望发现另一颗蓝色大理石星球
in hopes of finding another blue marble of a planet...
但是其它地球有可能比那要近得多
other Earths may be a lot closer than that.
所以想象一下回到35亿年前
So imagine going back 3 1/2 billion years ago...
来看一下我们的太阳系
and visiting our solar system.
你会看到这里有两颗蓝色大理石
You'd have seen two blue marbles here.
地球 有水 稠密的二氧化碳大气层 温暖的环境 生命
Earth--water, thick carbon dioxide atmosphere, warm conditions, life.
现在把想象稍微挪动一下
Now imagine moving a little over...
你看到了火星 表面有水
you see Mars-- water on the surface...
厚厚的二氧化碳大气层 温暖的环境 或许还有生命
thick carbon dioxide atmosphere, warm conditions, possibly life.
好 这两颗行星开始演化
Well, the two planets start evolving.
地球依然宜居
Earth stays habitable.
火星则不然
Mars doesn't.
金星与火星都刚好处在宜居的
Both Venus and Mars are just on the edge...
金发区域的边缘
of the Goldilocks zone of habitability.
两者都可能是失败地球的案例
Both may be cases of failed Earths.
一旦你掉了队
Once you fall off that path...
就可能永远都会不来了
you may never be able to come back.
火星对你需要长期维持宜居来说
Mars is a lesson for what you need...
是个教训
to maintain habitability for a long time.
其答案 我们认为就在于做大
And the answer, we think, turns out to be big.
你必须要大到如地球这样
You have to be as big as the Earth...
才能长期维持宜居
to maintain habitability for a long time.
火星太小了
Mars is too small.
正因为太小了 它无法循环其元素
Being too small, it has no way to recycle its elements...
无法长期持有自己的大气层
and has no way to hold onto its atmosphere for a long time.
所以 大小是关键
So, size matters.
火星现在太寒冷了
And while Mars is now too cold...
然而金星 我们另一颗或有的地球
Venus, our other would-be Earth...
却有着相反的问题
has the opposite problem.
它太热了
It's too hot.
它有点太靠近母星 太靠近太阳了
It was a little bit too close to its star, too close to the Sun.
它变热了 并且一直很热
It got hot, and it stayed hot.
因此所有的二氧化碳
And so all the carbon dioxide...
CO2等等 形成在地球上
the CO2 and so on, that formed on Earth...
也形成在了金星上
formed also on Venus.
不过在地球上 它被吸纳进了石头里
But on Earth, it was incorporated into rocks.
而在金星上 它留在了大气层里
On Venus, it stayed in the atmosphere...
那大气层基本上全球变暖到了N多级了
and the atmosphere, basically, is global warming to the Nth degree.
阳光射入 必定离不开了
Sunlight comes, and it must doesn't leave.
该星球就像是在烤炉里
That planet is like the inside of a pizza oven.
金星的失败是因为它诞生在了一个错误的地方
Venus failed because it was born in the wrong place.
火星的失败是因为生出了错误的个头
Mars failed because it was born the wrong size...
这样我们就有了一个有趣的故事
so that we have an interesting story here...
金星 地球 火星
Venus, Earth, and Mars.
金星处在了错误的位置
Venus is in the wrong place.
火星有个错误的个头
Mars is the wrong size.
地球是左右逢源 大小合适
Earth is the right place and the right size.
因此 如果我们的太阳系里的行星
So, if the planets in our solar system...
不是类似地球的伟大的候选人的话
aren't great candidates for being Earth-like...
我们最近的星际邻居 半人马座阿尔法星
our closest galactic neighbor, Alpha Centauri...
可能蕴藏着一颗类地行星
may harbor an Earth-like planet.
在4光年多一点的地方 按星际说法 就在隔壁
At a little over 4 light-years away, in galactic terms, it's next door.
我认为有极有可能
I think that there's a good chance...
有类地行星围绕着半人马座阿尔法星系里
that Earth-like planets are orbiting around...
一颗或两颗恒星运转
either one or both stars in the Alpha Centauri system.
天文学家格雷格.劳克林用计算机建模
Astronomer Greg Laughlin has done computer modeling...
来演示类地行星应该存在于该星系里
to show that Earth-like planets should exist in the system.
有很多理由说明半人马座阿尔法
There's a number of reasons why Alpha Centauri...
是在空中搜索地球的最佳星球
is the best star in the sky for hunting for Earths.
半人马座阿尔法非常近
Alpha Centauri is very close by.
半人马座阿尔法有两颗类似太阳的恒星
Alpha Centauri has two Sun-like stars.
半人马座阿尔法拥有大量的重元素之类的东西
Alpha Centauri has a large quantity of the kinds of heavy elements...
能够去打造行星
that go into building planets.
半人马座阿尔法星系离我们有多近呢?
How close is the Alpha Centauri system to us?
首先 想象把我们的太阳缩小到一粒沙子那么大
First, imagine shrinking our Sun down to the size of a grain of sand.
一粒沙子就是你肉眼所能看到的
A grain of sand is just about the smallest object...
最小的物体
that you can see with your eyes...
就是你用手指
and just about the smallest object...
刚好能感觉到的最小物体
that you can actually feel with your fingers.
比例是太阳就一粒沙子大
And the scale where the Sun is the size of a grain of sand...
半人马座阿尔法星系是三粒沙子
the Alpha Centauri system is three more sand grains...
位于5英里外的地方
placed about five miles away.
好 如果我们想在半人马座阿尔法里 看到类似不错的星系
Now, if we wanted to get a similarly good system to Alpha Centauri...
我们就必须一路越过地平线
we'd have to actually go all the way over the horizon...
去寻觅那个不错的恒星系
to find another stellar system that's good.
事实证明 半人马座阿尔法星系里的恒星
And it turns out that the stars of the Alpha Centauri system...
应该具有大量构成行星的原料
should have plenty of raw materials to make planets out of.
半人马座阿尔法的金属度超过了我们的太阳
Alpha Centauri has a higher metallicity than our own Sun does.
那就说明 行星的形成是个
And that implies that planet formation was a process...
相对较容易发生在该星系里的过程
that took place relatively easily in that system.
最后 尤为重要的是
And last, but not least...
半人马座阿尔法星的两颗主星提供了额外的好处
Alpha Centauri's two main stars provide an additional benefit.
初步的迹象表明
The initial indications show...
没有木星大小的行星
that there are no Jupiter-mass planets...
存在于半人马座阿尔法星系里
in the Alpha Centauri system.
那就更加直截了当地让类地行星
That makes it more streightforward...
形成在一颗或两颗恒星的周围
for terrestrial planets to form around either or both of the stars.
那是因为气体巨星是围绕
That's because large gas giants form around cores of ice...
大如我们整个地球的冰核形成的
that are as big as our entire Earth.
因此这些巨星需要大量的冷却空间来形成这些冰核
So these giants need a lot of cold space to form these cores.
想想木星形成在离我们太阳多远的地方
Think of how far out Jupiter is from our Sun.
然而 一旦你有了两颗恒星交错运行在
However, when you have two stars with overlapping orbits...
半人马座阿尔法这样的星系里
in a system like Alpha Centauri...
那么星系里就不存在有足够大 足够冷的空间
there isn't a space in the system that's big enough and cold enough...
允许这些气体巨星的形成
to allow the formation of these gas giants.
因此我们预计有行星存在于
So we expect that the planets that exist...
半人马座阿尔法星系里 如果它们存在
in the Alpha Centauri system, if they are there...
就会是地球 火星 金星之类的类地行星
they're terrestrial planets like the Earth or Mars or Venus.
它们不会是木星或土星之类的气体巨星
They're not gas giant planets like Jupiter or Saturn.
要是我们真能调查出在我们这部分宇宙中
What if we could actually survey...
有多少地球又会怎样呢?
how many Earths are in our part of the universe?
要是我们能够直接看透数光年外的
What if we could peer directly into the atmosphere of another Earth...
另一个地球的大气层又当如何呢?
that was light-years away?
为了发现另一个地球
In order to find another Earth...
天文学家必须克服巨大的技术挑战
astronomers have to eventually overcome...
去观察遥远的行星
the huge technical challenges of how to view a distant planet.
那是航天局已经解决的问题
It's a problem that NASA has tackled...
诸如月球竞赛
much like the race for the Moon...
有延续数十年的规划
with plans that stretch out over decades.
首个日外行星发现任务将是开普勒号
The first exoplanet-finding mission will be Kepler...
将在2009年升空
which launches in 2009.
航天局的调查项目的命名
The NASA survey project is named...
来自17世纪的天文学家约翰内斯.开普勒
after the 17th-century astronomer Johannes Kepler...
他发现了行星的运动定律
who discovered the laws of planetary motion.
开普勒要做的非常简单
What Kepler will do is so utterly simple...
但非常地强大
and yet extraordinarily powerful...
它让我热泪盈眶
it brings tears to my eyes.
开普勒所做的就是简单作为一架太空望远镜
What Kepler will do is simply be a space-borne telescope...
凝视天鹅座和天琴座
and stare at the constellations Cygnus and Lyra...
连续不停地拍照
taking picture after picture after picture...
只要目标恒星在类地行星遮挡其星光时发生暗淡
with the goal of looking for stars that dim...when an Earth-like planet blocks some of the starlight.
它将是首次
And it will be the first time...
我们人类侦查围绕其它恒星的
that we humans detect other Earth-like planets...
其它类地行星
around other stars.
开普勒的首席调查员是威廉.博鲁茨基
The principal investigator for Kepler is William Borucki.
他25年来一直在力挺该任务
He's been championing the mission for 25 years.
开普勒实际上是个太空任务
Kepler, basically, is a space mission...
送上去一架大口径望远镜
that puts up a very large telescope.
它很像是一个摄像机
It's very much like a camcorder.
它不停地拍摄那些恒星
It's always taking pictures of these stars...
把信息发回给你
sending that information back to you.
该任务是个相对较小的调查项目
The mission is a comparatively small survey project...
去观察固定的空域 初定时间为三年半
to look at a fixed portion of the sky for an initial time of 3 1/2 years.
开普勒的主要成果将为我们提供统计数字
The main result from Kepler will be to give us a statistical count.
就是对象的人头数
It's a head count of what the population is.
也就是 你看到有多少小行星
You know, how many small planets do you have...
有多少大行星
and how many large planets do you have?
开普勒的成果回过头来
Kepler's results will, in turn...
用来帮助决定
be used to help decide what will be built...
构建下一代的行星发现任务
for the next generation of planet-finding missions.
开普勒实际上是前进的第一步
Kepler really is one step along the way.
它试图找到地球
It's to try to find Earths...
厘清它们是否比比皆是
and find out whether they're frequent.
如果它们比比皆是 就必定是很密集
lf they are frequent, they must be close...
这样我们就可以打造最合适的仪器
so we can build a modest instrument.
如果我们没有发现好多地球 那么那就意味着
If we don't find many Earths, what that means is...
在你发现另一个地球之前
before you're going to find another one...
你将不得不观察更大距离的空间
you're going to have to look a huge distance into space.
这样你就不得不打造更大
So you're going to have to build...
更昂贵的仪器
a much bigger, much more expensive instrument.
人类史上所构思的
The most majestic, spectacular telescope...
最宏伟壮观的太空望远镜
ever conceived by humanity...
就是所谓的类地行星发现者
is something called the Terrestrial Planet Finder.
它将是太空中一个庞大的望远镜
It will be an enormous telescope in space...
坦白说有可能耗资数十亿美元
frankly probably costing several billion dollars.
但是它的作用是无与伦比的
But what it will do is absolutely unique.
它将是首个望远镜
It will be the first telescope...
用来拍摄其它类地行星
to take pictures of other Earth-like planets.
为了直接目睹我们太阳系外的行星
To directly view a planet outside our solar system...
一个全新的望远镜技术正在研发
a whole new telescope technology is being developed.
为了构建类地行星发现者
To construct the Terrestrial Planet Finder...
针对其主星的强光来拍摄地球
that will image Earths against the glare of their host stars...
我们需要某些全新的光学技术
we need some entirely new optical technology...
这种技术 坦白说我们尚未发明出来
a technology that frankly we haven't invented yet.
挫折是明摆的
The frustration is just palpable...
我们其实大致知道如何去发现其它地球
that we actually know vaguely how to detect other Earths...
但是我们确实不知道如何去构建能够达到目的的光学
but we don't know exactly how to build the optics to do so.
航天局预想类地行星发现者
NASA envisions the Terrestrial Planet Finder...
是两个完全不同却又相辅相成的
as a suite of two very different...
创新望远镜的组合
but complementary advanced-concept telescopes.
首先是 可视光的日冕观测仪
The first, the visible light coronagraph...
结合巨大的镜面光学望远镜
consists of a large optical telescope with a mirror...
至少要比哈勃望远镜精准100倍
at least 100 times more precise than the Hubble Space Telescope.
日冕观测仪是单个望远镜
A coronagraph is a single telescope...
用来收集星光
which collects the light from a star...
将光聚焦到后部
and focuses the light at the back end...
和普通望远镜没两样
like a normal telescope.
但是 在那里 我们会遮挡恒星发出的光
Except, at that point, we block the light from the star...
会试图让行星发出的光通过
and we try to let the light from the planet come through.
这样一来 你就避免了散光进入仪器
By doing this, you cancel out the scattered light in the instrument...
这样你就让自己能够看到这颗行星了
and so you allow yourself to be able to look at this planet...
它要比主星昏暗百亿倍
which is 10 billion times fainter than the main star.
其次类地行星发现者
The second Terrestrial Planet Finder mission...
将是一架干涉仪
will be an interferometer.
干涉仪的工作就是获取射入的星光
An interferometer works by taking the light from a star that comes in...
用两架甚至更多的望远镜来捕获它
and capturing it with two telescopes, sometimes more.
这种组合光就可以以这种方式
And this combined light can be arranged in such a way...
将恒星发出的光给遮挡了
that the light from the star disappears.
那是个好主意
That's good in the sense...
你现在可以看到它旁边的行星了
that you now can look at the planet that's next to it...
行星发出的光就不会看不见了
and the light from the planet does not disappear.
那就是干涉仪的魔力所在
That's the magic of an interferometer.
为了尽善尽美 更新精度的掌控技术
To get all of this done, new levels of precision...
需要得到进一步地完善
in control and command technologies need to be perfected...
有些东西可能需要几年功夫来进行研发
something that could take years to develop.
追寻天文学上的圣杯
The quest for the holy grail of astronomy...
太阳系外的另一个地球
another Earth outside our solar system...
已经驱使科学家们去思索
has pushed scientists to speculate...
这样的发现将会如何影响到我们
about how such a discovery could affect us.
我认为一旦我们发现有另一个地球的存在
I think if we find another Earth out there...
那将会对社会产生巨大的影响
that's going to have an enormous impact on society.
我认为了解到我们并不孤独
I think to know that we are not alone...
我们只是N多生命潜在的居所之一
that we are one of many potential sites for life...
我想将会引发人们思维模式的转变
I think will cause a huge paradigm shift in people's thinking.
但是也有可能
But there's also the possibility...
我们可能就是宇宙间的天之骄子
that we may be unique in the universe...
我们很有可能发现有类地行星
and that we may well find Earth-like planets...
但却并无智能的存在
but no intelligent beings on them.
我们必须保持一点冷静
We have to remember something a little sobering.
仍然有可能我们人类...是一个意外的进化
It is still possible that we humans...are a accident of evolutionary tree
这发生在2万年前的非洲东部大草原
that has occurred in a savanna East Africa 2 million years ago
已失去了类人非常罕见的间隔
and has lost the humanoid very rare intervals,
并没有发生在4.5亿年前
that has not happened in 4.5 million years on the earth.
我们很可能是银河系里极罕见的
It is possible that we are being extremely rare in the Milky Way.
事实上 这可能是我们这样一种...
In fact, this may be our so that one species...
探索及我们是第一个研究人员
to explore and we are the first researchers.
在这种情况下 我们的命运将会找到我们的根
In this case, our destiny will be to find our roots
化学和生物的星星
chemical and biological among the stars.
我们有一幅图画
we are have a picture
确实漂亮
really beautiful.